Guide to the Hendrik Willem van Loon papers, 1884-1972.
Van Loon, Hendrick Willem papers,
- Series IV. Manuscript material
  - Subseries IVa. Book Manuscripts
    - R. V. R. Volume 2, p. 843-907 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - R. V. R. Volume 2, p. 908-975 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - R. V. R. Volume 2, p. 976-1013 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - R. V. R. Volume 2, p. 1014-1056 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - R. V. R. Volume 2, p. 1057-1098 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - R. V. R. Volume 2, p. 1099-1152 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - R. V. R. Volume 2, p. 1153-1221 (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Report to St. Peter (The New Perspective), carbon, 5 pgs. (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Report to St. Peter (The New Perspective), typescript, 8 pgs. (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Report to St. Peter (The New Perspective), typescript and carbon forward (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Report to St. Peter (The New Perspective), typescript forward (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - Report to St. Peter (The New Perspective), carbon, Chapter 1 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Report to St. Peter (The New Perspective), handwritten draft, 16 pgs. (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - Report to St. Peter (The New Perspective), typescript forward, 22 pgs. (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - Report to St. Peter, handwritten and carbon title page typescript Chapter 1 (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - Report to St. Peter, typescript 2 pgs. (Box 22, Folder 31)
    - Report to St. Peter, handwritten draft, forward (Box 22, Folder 32)
    - Report to St. Peter, prologue, p. 1-34 (Box 22, Folder 33)
    - Report to St. Peter, handwritten draft p. 1-46 (Box 22, Folder 34)
    - Report to St. Peter, p. 47-103 (Box 22, Folder 35)
    - Report to St. Peter, p. 104-141 (Box 22, Folder 36)
    - Report to St. Peter, p. 142-180 (Box 22, Folder 37)
    - Report to St. Peter, p. 181-204 (Box 22, Folder 38)
    - Report to St. Peter, p. 205-250 (Box 22, Folder 39)
    - Report to St. Peter, p. 251-303 (Box 22, Folder 40)
    - Report to St. Peter, carbon. 1-50 (Box 22, Folder 41)
    - Report to St. Peter, p. 51-100 (Box 22, Folder 42)
    - Report to St. Peter, p. 101-150 (Box 22, Folder 43)
    - Report to St. Peter, p. 151-181 (Box 22, Folder 44)
    - Report to St. Peter, carbon, dedication pg. and list of illustrations, letter from Jimmie to Wallace (Box 22, Folder 45)
    - Report to St. Peter, annotated typescript prologue (Box 22, Folder 46)
    - Report to St. Peter, p. 1-31 (Box 22, Folder 47)
    - Report to St. Peter, p. 32-74 (Box 22, Folder 48)
    - Report to St. Peter, p. 75-110 (Box 22, Folder 49)
    - Report to St. Peter, p. 111-145 (Box 22, Folder 50)
    - Report to St. Peter, p. 146-180 (Box 22, Folder 51)
    - Ships and How They Sailed the Seven Seas, carbon index (Box 22, Folder 52)
    - Ships and How They Sailed the Seven Seas, annotated typescript, p. 1-21 title page, dedication and table of contents (Box 22, Folder 53)
    - Ships and How They Sailed the Seven Seas, annotated typescript p. 22-61 (Box 22, Folder 54)
    - Ships and How They Sailed the Seven Seas, p. 62-92 (Box 22, Folder 55)
    - Ships and How They Sailed the Seven Seas, p. 93-125 (Box 22, Folder 56)
    - Ships and How They Sailed the Seven Seas, p. 126-159 (Box 22, Folder 57)
    - Ships and How They Sailed the Seven Seas, p. 160-193 (Box 22, Folder 58)
    - Ships and How They Sailed the Seven Seas, p. 194-212 (Box 22, Folder 59)
    - Ships and How They Sailed the Seven Seas, annotated typescript, Copy A forward, title page, dedication and table of contents (Box 22, Folder 60)
    - Ships and How They Sailed the Seven Seas, annotated typescript p. 7-40 (Box 22, Folder 61)
    - Ships and How They Sailed the Seven Seas, p. 41-81 (Box 22, Folder 62)
    - Ships and How They Sailed the Seven Seas, p. 82-109 (Box 22, Folder 63)
    - Ships and How They Sailed the Seven Seas, annotated typescript continued p. 110-138 (Box 22, Folder 64)
    - Ships and How They Sailed the Seven Seas, p. 139-169 (Box 22, Folder 65)
    - Ships and How They Sailed the Seven Seas, p. 170-202 (Box 22, Folder 66)
    - The Story of the Bible, annotated carbon and handwritten p. 1-24 (Box 22, Folder 67)
    - The Story of the Bible, annotated handwritten p. 25-55 (Box 22, Folder 68)
    - The Story of the Bible, annotated typescript p. 56-62 (Box 22, Folder 69)
    - The Story of the Bible, annotated handwritten p. 63-103 (Box 22, Folder 69)
    - The Story of the Bible, annotated typescript p. 104-140 (Box 22, Folder 70)
    - The Story of the Bible, annotated typescript and carbon p. 141-168 (Box 22, Folder 71)
    - The Story of the Bible, annotated handwritten and carbon p. 169-203 (Box 22, Folder 72)
    - The Story of the Bible, p. 204-240 (Box 22, Folder 73)
    - The Story of the Bible, annotated typescript and carbon p. 241-273 (Box 22, Folder 74)
    - The Story of the Bible, annotated handwritten and carbon p. 274-329 (Box 22, Folder 75)
    - Story of Mankind (final chapter), annotated handwritten, 6 pgs. (Box 22, Folder 76)
    - Pacific, carbon index and p. 1-10 (Box 22, Folder 77)
    - Pacific, annotated typescript p. 11-43 (missing p. 19 and 20) (Box 22, Folder 78)
    - Pacific, annotated typescript p. 44-84 (with a few handwritten pgs.) (Box 22, Folder 79)
    - Pacific, annotated typescript p. 85-130 (with a few handwritten pgs (Box 22, Folder 80)
    - Pacific, p. 131-169 (Box 22, Folder 81)
    - Pacific, p. 170-205 (Box 22, Folder 82)
    - Pacific, p. 206-215 (Box 22, Folder 83)
    - Pacific, handwritten draft p. 1-40 (Box 22, Folder 84)
    - Pacific, p. 16-23 (Box 22, Folder 85)
    - Pacific, p. 11-20 (Box 22, Folder 86)
    - Pacific, p. 41-75 (missing p. 48) (Box 22, Folder 87)
    - Pacific, p. 76-110 (Box 22, Folder 88)
    - Pacific, p. 111-155 (missing p. 144) (Box 22, Folder 89)
    - Pacific, handwritten draft continued p. 156-189 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Pacific, p. 190-230 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Pacific, p. 231-280 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Pacific, p. 281-324 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Pacific, p. 325-360 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Pacific, p. 361-400 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Pacific, p. 401-445 (missing p. 425) (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Pacific, p. 446-480 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Pacific, p. 481-500 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Pacific, p. 501-515 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Pacific, p. 215-223 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Pacific, p. 221-229 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Pacific, annotated typescript index p. 1-33 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Pacific, p. 34-70 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Pacific, p. 71-109 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Pacific, p. 110-155 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Pacific, p. 156-200 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Pacific, p. 201-231 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Thomas Jefferson, handwritten prologue, typescript forward, carbon list of characters (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Thomas Jefferson, handwritten, typescript and carbon copies of dedication, handwritten notes on chapters (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Thomas Jefferson, handwritten draft p. 1-10 pg. 1 and 2 from Chapter 1 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Thomas Jefferson, carbon of notes on chapters handwritten notes (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Thomas Jefferson, annotated carbon p. 1-35 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Thomas Jefferson, p. 36-60, 68-80, 84, 87 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Thomas Jefferson, annotated typescript p. 1-31 (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Thomas Jefferson, p. 32-66 and 3 pg. of afterthoughts (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Thomas Jefferson, handwritten draft notes p. 1-20 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Thomas Jefferson, p. 21-51 (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - Thomas Jefferson, p. 52-78 (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Thomas Jefferson, p. 89-122 and 3 pg. of afterthoughts (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - Thomas Jefferson, annotated typescript p. 1-35 (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - Thomas Jefferson, p. 36-60 (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - Thomas Jefferson, p. 61-89 and 9 pg. of afterthoughts (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - Van Loon's Lives, handwritten, typescript and carbon introduction; Wings booklet dated Sept. 1942 (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - Historical Dinners Nieuw Veere, carbon list of guests 4 pgs. (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - Historical Dinners Nieuw Veere, St. Francis, title page (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - Historical Dinners Nieuw Veere, Dedication page (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - Historical Dinners Nieuw Veere, Netherlands; carbon dedication; letter to van Loon from Princess Juliana; postcard (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - Historical Dinners Nieuw Veere, Napoleon's Mother; annotated typescript and carbon, 3 pgs. (Box 23, Folder 39)
    - Historical Dinners Nieuw Veere, Erasmus; annotated typescript p. 1-25 (Box 23, Folder 40)
    - Historical Dinners Nieuw Veere, p. 26-60 (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - Historical Dinners Nieuw Veere, p. 61-85 (Box 23, Folder 42)
    - Historical Dinners Nieuw Veere, p. 86-106 (Box 23, Folder 43)
    - Historical Dinners Nieuw Veere, Beethoven; typescript and carbon of letter from Beethoven (Box 23, Folder 44)
    - Historical Dinners Nieuw Veere, introduction, typescript and handwritten list of guests (Box 23, Folder 45)
    - Historical Dinners Nieuw Veere, miscellaneous draft, foreword (Box 23, Folder 46)
    - Historical Dinners Nieuw Veere, miscellaneous draft, dedication (Box 23, Folder 47)
    - Historical Dinners Nieuw Veere, handwritten draft, list of guests miscellaneous draft, dedication (Box 23, Folder 48)
    - Historical Dinners Nieuw Veere, miscellaneous guest list (Box 23, Folder 49)
    - Historical Dinners Nieuw Veere, annotated typescript p. 1-40 (Box 23, Folder 50)
    - Historical Dinners Nieuw Veere, p. 41-80 (Box 23, Folder 51)
    - Historical Dinners Nieuw Veere, p. 81-116 (Box 23, Folder 52)
    - Historical Dinners Nieuw Veere, p. 117-150 (Box 23, Folder 53)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, annotated typescript continued p. 151-179 (Box 23, Folder 54)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 180-230 (Box 23, Folder 55)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 231-275 (Box 23, Folder 56)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 276-309 (Box 23, Folder 57)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 310-350 (Box 23, Folder 58)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 351-376 (Box 23, Folder 59)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 377-420 (Box 23, Folder 60)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 421-460 (Box 23, Folder 61)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 461-500 (Box 23, Folder 62)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 501-541 (Box 23, Folder 63)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 542-580 (Box 23, Folder 64)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 581-625 (Box 23, Folder 65)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 626-665 (Box 23, Folder 66)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 666-700 (Box 23, Folder 67)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 701-741 (Box 23, Folder 68)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 742-773 (Box 23, Folder 69)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, carbon p. 1-42 (Box 23, Folder 70)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 43-80 (Box 23, Folder 71)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 81-120 (Box 23, Folder 72)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 121-175 (Box 23, Folder 73)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 176-203 (Box 23, Folder 74)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 204-250 (Box 23, Folder 75)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 251-315 (Box 23, Folder 76)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 316-360 (Box 23, Folder 77)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 361-403 (Box 23, Folder 78)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, carbon continued p. 404-445 (Box 23, Folder 79)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 446-491 (Box 23, Folder 80)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 492-525 (Box 23, Folder 81)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 526-560 (Box 23, Folder 82)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 561-589 (Box 23, Folder 83)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 590-635 (Box 23, Folder 84)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 636-680 (Box 23, Folder 85)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 681-715 (Box 23, Folder 86)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 716-745 (Box 23, Folder 87)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 746-773 and several extra pages (Box 23, Folder 88)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, title page, handwritten draft p. 15-40 (Box 23, Folder 89)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 41-75 (Box 23, Folder 90)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 76-96 (Box 23, Folder 91)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, annotated typescript p. 1-40 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, handwritten draft p. 108-140 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 141-180 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 181-210 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Van Loon's Lives Nieuw Veere, p. 211-250 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Dinner Party, pg. 252-286 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Dinner Party, p. 287-320 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Dinner Party, p. 321-355 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Dinner Party, p. 356-390 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Dinner Party, p. 391-435 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, handwritten draft continued p. 436-470 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 471-500 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 501-540 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 541-575 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 576-609 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 610-645 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 646-680 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 681-715 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 716-750 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 751-785 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 786-820 (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 821-850 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 851-880 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 881-914 (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 917-950 (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 951-975 (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 976-1000 (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 1001-1035 (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 1036-1070 (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 1071-1105 (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 1106-1130 (Box 24, Folder 31)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 1131-1165 (Box 24, Folder 32)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 1166-1200 (Box 24, Folder 33)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 1201-1235 (Box 24, Folder 34)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, pi 1236-1246 (Box 24, Folder 35)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, handwritten draft continued p. 1267-1300 (Box 24, Folder 36)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 1301-1335 (Box 24, Folder 37)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 1336-1370 (Box 24, Folder 38)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 1371-1411 (Box 24, Folder 39)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 1412-1454 (Box 24, Folder 40)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, p. 1555-1590 (Box 24, Folder 41)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, possible insertions ? p. 1-50 (Box 24, Folder 42)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, possible insertions ? p. 51-85 (Box 24, Folder 43)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party, title page, list of guests, forward (Box 24, Folder 44)
    - Nieuw Veere, annotated typescript p. 1-35 (Box 24, Folder 45)
    - Nieuw Veere, p. 36-68 (Box 24, Folder 46)
    - Nieuw Veere, p. 69-100 (Box 24, Folder 47)
    - Nieuw Veere, p. 101-135 (Box 24, Folder 48)
    - Nieuw Veere, p. 136-167 (Box 24, Folder 49)
    - Nieuw Veere, p. 168-198 (Box 24, Folder 50)
    - Nieuw Veere, p. 199-235 (Box 24, Folder 51)
    - Nieuw Veere, p. 236-270 (Box 24, Folder 52)
    - Nieuw Veere, p. 271-305 (Box 24, Folder 53)
    - Nieuw Veere, p. 306-340 (Box 24, Folder 54)
    - Nieuw Veere, p. 341-375 (Box 24, Folder 55)
    - Nieuw Veere, p. 376-406 (Box 24, Folder 56)
    - Nieuw Veere, p. 407-440 (Box 24, Folder 57)
    - Nieuw Veere, p. 441-475 (Box 24, Folder 58)
    - Nieuw Veere, p. 476-502 (Box 24, Folder 59)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party Nieuw Veere, annotated typescript continued p. 503-540 (Box 24, Folder 60)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party Nieuw Veere, p. 541-570 (Box 24, Folder 61)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party Nieuw Veere, p. 571-607 (Box 24, Folder 62)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party Nieuw Veere, p. 608-645 (Box 24, Folder 63)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party Nieuw Veere, p. 646-671 (Box 24, Folder 64)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party Nieuw Veere, p. 672-695 (Box 24, Folder 65)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party Nieuw Veere, p. 696-730 (Box 24, Folder 66)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party Nieuw Veere, p. 731-773 (Box 24, Folder 67)
    - Van Loon's Lives Dinner Party Nieuw Veere, annotated copies of various pgs. (Box 24, Folder 68)
    - The Average Man, carbon, chapter notes and dedication (Box 24, Folder 69)
    - The Average Man, handwritten, typescript and carbon copies of title page and forward (Box 24, Folder 70)
    - The Average Man, The Mill of the Gods, typescript and carbon title page, forward, and dedication (Box 24, Folder 71)
    - The Average Man, handwritten forward (Box 24, Folder 72)
    - The Average Man, annotated typescript and handwritten forward, handwritten draft of Chapter 1 and miscellaneous pages (Box 24, Folder 73)
    - The Average Man, A New History for a New World, typescript forward and p. 1-27 (Box 24, Folder 74)
    - The Average Man, p. 28-44 (Box 24, Folder 75)
    - The Average Man, handwritten/typescript forward (Box 24, Folder 76)
    - The Average Man, carbon and typescript dedication, forward and title page (Box 24, Folder 77)
    - The Average Man, carbon, dedication and forward (Box 24, Folder 78)
    - The Hidden Door, Jan. 3, 1944 carbon, title page, forward and miscellaneous pages handwritten, title page, forward, and dedication (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - In Praise of Freedom, typescript title page and dedication carbon forward, title page and miscellaneous pages (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Jean Navarrin, miscellaneous pages (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - The Eighteenth Century, Aug. 20, 1943 handwritten and carbon forward (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - The Eighteenth Century, handwritten dedication and miscellaneous draft pages (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - The Eighteenth Century, typescript title page, dedication, and list of characters (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - The Eighteenth Century, carbon title page, dedication and list of characters (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - The World, handwritten introduction carbon forward typescript letter from publisher (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - The World, annotated typescript introduction, dedication and forward (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - The World, typescript and carbon introduction (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Garden of the Poets, July 12, 1940 handwritten draft p. 1-42 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Garden of the Poets, p. 43-69 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Garden of the Poets, typescript and carbon p. 1-21 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - The New Academy, Oct. 26, 1940 carbon introduction, several typescript pages (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - If We Had Been There, Feb. 12, 1941 typescript title page and forward; miscellaneous manuscript pages (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Let Us Cultivate Our Garden, Feb. 15, 1941 miscellaneous manuscript pages (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Education, May 20, 1942 miscellaneous manuscript pages (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - A Short History of Music, Aug. 9, 1942 miscellaneous manuscript pages (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - The Prince and His Men, Feb. 2, 1943 miscellaneous manuscript pages (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Force and Freedom, Feb. 2, 1943 miscellaneous manuscript pages (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Confessions of Faith, Feb. 23, 1943 miscellaneous manuscript pages (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Hate, February 1943 miscellaneous manuscript pages (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Hannibal's Elephant, Mar. 24, 1943 miscellaneous manuscript pages (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Hannibal's Elephant, forward and additional miscellaneous manuscript pages (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - The Netherlands, Nov. 13, 1943 handwritten draft p. 1-45 (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - The Netherlands, miscellaneous manuscript pages (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - A Short History of Democracy, miscellaneous manuscript pages (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - A Short History of Democracy, miscellaneous manuscript pages (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - A Short History of Democracy, miscellaneous manuscript pages (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - F.D.R., annotated typescript p. 1-35 (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - F.D.R., carbon p. 1-23 (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - F.D.R., miscellaneous manuscript pages (Box 25, Folder 33)
    - F.D.R., miscellaneous manuscript pages (Box 25, Folder 34)
    - F.D.R., miscellaneous manuscript pages (Box 25, Folder 35)
    - F.D.R., miscellaneous manuscript pages (Box 25, Folder 36)
    - Holland Will Live, miscellaneous manuscript pages (Box 25, Folder 37)
    - N/A, miscellaneous manuscript pages (Box 25, Folder 38)
    - Miscellaneous talks West Indies, miscellaneous manuscript pages (Box 25, Folder 39)
    - Gold, miscellaneous manuscript pages (Box 25, Folder 40)
    - Gideon Ginther and God, an 8-page story with additional miscellaneous manuscript pages (Box 25, Folder 41)
    - The Unfinished Manuscript, annotated typescript, 39 pages (Box 25, Folder 42)
    - RCA, annotated typescript, 29 pages (Box 25, Folder 43)
    - RCA, miscellaneous manuscript pages (Box 25, Folder 44)
    - RCA, carbon, 24 pages (Box 25, Folder 45)
    - N/A, handwritten draft (Box 25, Folder 46)
    - N/A, handwritten manuscript (Box 25, Folder 47)
    - N/A, p. 1-47 p. 48-97 (Box 25, Folder 48)
    - Beethoven, miscellaneous manuscript pages (Box 25, Folder 49)
    - N/A, miscellaneous manuscript pages (Box 25, Folder 50)
    - N/A, dedication to grandson (Box 25, Folder 51)
    - N/A, miscellaneous introductions and dedications (Box 25, Folder 52)
  - Subseries IVb. Articles
    - "Why Holland Should Be Neutral," February 26, 1915, New York Times (Box 25, Folder 53)
    - "A Bird's Eye View of the War," c. February 1915, Century Magazine (Box 25, Folder 54)
    - "The Citizen Army of Holland," June 1916, National Geographic (Box 25, Folder 55)
    - "The Story of The Bible," March 1923, McCall's (Box 25, Folder 56)
    - "What to do With Johnny This Summer," ca. 1924 (Box 25, Folder 57)
    - "The Author's Story of 'The Story of The Bible'," ca. 192? (Box 25, Folder 58)
    - "Intruding," April 1931 (Box 25, Folder 59)
    - "Meet The Commentator," newspaper columnNov. 12 - -Nov. 30, 1934 (Box 25, Folder 60)
    - "Meet The Commentator," newspaper columnDec. 1-Dec. 31, 1934 (Box 25, Folder 61)
    - "Meet The Commentator," newspaper columnFeb. 1-Feb. 28, 1935 (Box 25, Folder 62)
    - "Meet The Commentator," newspaper columnMar. 1-Mar. 30, 1935 (Box 25, Folder 63)
    - "Meet The Commentator," newspaper columnApr. 1-Apr. 20, 1935 (Box 25, Folder 64)
    - "From Raw Reindeer Steak to Fried Nightingale Tongues," March 17, 1935, Pictorial Review (Box 25, Folder 65)
    - "N/A,", Pictorial Review II (Box 25, Folder 66)
    - "The End of The Great Migrations," April 11, 1935 (Box 25, Folder 67)
    - "The Only Trouble With Revolution is the Revolution Itself," 1935 (Box 25, Folder 68)
    - "Mussert-Would-Be Dictator of Holland," August 1942, Tomorrow (Box 25, Folder 69)
    - "For Mungo," written October 1943 published March 1944, Skylark Magazine (Box 25, Folder 70)
    - "How The People of The Netherlands Learned to Hate," Jan. -Feb. 1944 The, Norseman (Box 25, Folder 71)
    - "Well Done Knickerbocker," Feb. 11, 1944, Knickerbocker Weekly (Box 25, Folder 72)
    - "An Introduction by Van Loon," ca. May 17, 1941 (Box 25, Folder 73)
    - "On a Certain Bulbous Herb-Commonly Known as the Tulip," March 18, ? (Box 25, Folder 74)
    - "Book Review," n.d. (Box 25, Folder 75)